tes.com 2017-11-23

# Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy | Tes

This is the Privacy Policy that applies to use of websites ("Sites") and services ("Service") which are under the control of TES Global Limited of 26 Red Lion Square, London, WC1R 4HQ (" **TES Global** "). References to "we", "our" and "us" are references to TES Global.

We take your privacy seriously and we are committed to keeping your information private. We have notified the Information Commissioner's Office that we will process your personal data in accordance with the UK Data Protection Act 1998.

This Privacy Policy explains what we do with data relating to you. If you have any questions about this or about personal information that we may hold about you please contact us by email at [privacy@tes.com](mailto:privacy@tes.com).

By clicking "I Agree Finish" or "Accept" during registration or by purchasing a product or subscribing to a service or by using this Site and submitting your personal information to the website or by email, you consent to our processing of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you do not accept this privacy policy you should not submit your personal data to us and you may find that you will not be able to make full use of the website and its services.

### **Scope of this policy**

The TES Global Sites and Services include, and without limitation:

  * tes.com
  * tesconnect.com
  * tsleducation.com
  * teshirewire.com
  * tesprime.co.uk
  * teachingexhibitions.co.uk
  * timeshighereducation.co.uk
  * hirewire.co.uk
  * tslshop.co.uk
  * iboard.co.uk
  * tespro.com
  * tesspag.com
  * tesphonics.com
  * tesclassroom.com
  * tesdigital.com
  * tes.co.uk/labs
  * wikispaces.com

and the website from which these terms of use were accessed from.

Sites may contain links to other web sites over which we have no control. TES Global is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other web sites to which you choose to link from this site. We strongly encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other web sites so you can understand how they may collect, use and share your information.

### **Information about your visits to our sites**

We collect personal information from visitors to this website through the use of on-line forms and every time you e-mail us your details. We also collect information about the transactions you may undertake including details of payment methods used.

We automatically gather information about your visits to our sites. This includes demographic data and browsing patterns. This is used to build up marketing profiles, to aid strategic development, to manage our relationship with advertisers and to audit usage of the site.

### **Use of cookies**

We may use 'cookies' to identify you and your use of Sites when you visit this and associated sites to confirm that you are logged in and to build up a demographic profile. A cookie is a small collection of data sent by a web server to a web browser, which lets the server to collect information back from the browser. Our use of cookies also may allow registered users to be presented with a personalised version of the site.

You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use products or services that require you to "sign in" and you may not be able to take full advantage of offerings or use on all TES Global Sites.

For further information please see our Cookie Policy below and for more independent information about cookies, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### **Use of personal information**

Contact and other details you supply as part of the registration process will be used by us to authenticate your identity, deal with your inquiries and requests and to provide you with our services (including to process your orders and administer your account).

We may also use  _ **your personal**_  information to personalise aspects of our services, to carry out market research surveys, to contact you about opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you and to provide you with updates about developments on the sites and information about the products and services we offer.  _ **Information may also be used for marketing and strategic development purposes**_ , for example to identify trends usage. It is your responsibility to ensure that any information submitted as part of the registration process, to your user account or as part of an application to a job posting is accurate and up to date.

If you have elected to receive information about our products or services or the products or services offered jointly with or on behalf of other organisations and/or "alerts" from us via email (by creating an alert in the Jobs by Email service) and would like at any time to unsubscribe from this service, please email us at [info@tes.com](mailto:info@tes.com) [or click on the " **unsubscribe** " link at the bottom of an email].

### **Disclosures**

In order to provide Sites services we will share your personal information with other organisations such as partners and third party service providers.

You should be aware that some of the Sites and Services are hosted by us on behalf of those recruiting institutions that have signed-up to process job vacancies and applications via the Service (for example www.teshirewire.com). In order to provide these Services we will share your personal information with such institutions. We do not verify the identity or the nature of the business of such organisations and we are not in any way responsible for any use or misuse of your personal data by those institutions. To the extent you have any concerns about an institution's handling of your personal data you should get in touch with that institution.

We will not disclose any information we keep about you to any third parties, except for (1) other companies in the TES Global group of companies, (2) where you have agreed to the sharing of data, (3) any suppliers we engage to provide services which involve processing data on our behalf. We will not disclose your personal information to third parties outside the TES Global and its joint venture companies if it is to be used and controlled for commercial purposes. We reserve the right to disclose your personal information to third parties outside the TES Global and its joint venture companies, including, as illustrative examples, government bodies, law enforcement and credit reference agencies, professional services like law and accountancy firms, cyber security breach management providers and regulators, for non-commercial purposes.

### **Content posted by you**

If you post any personal information to any of our public forums, this information will immediately be made available to other users throughout the world who may use it to send you unsolicited communications. In some circumstances we may display pseudonyms that identify you as a user but not your actual personal information (your username for example) when you post material to the website to allow users to identify each other.

If you post any content in breach of our Sites terms of use we may inform any relevant third parties such as your employer, school email/Internet provider and law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour.

### **Third Party Privacy Policies**

Our website uses ad servers (such as Doubleclick) to serve the advertisements that you see on pages from our Sites. That partner uses cookies to collect information about your use of our Website to help target ads to your interests. To find out more about the use of cookies and the information-gathering practices and opt-out procedures of DoubleClick please go to <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy>.

Please note that if you do disable cookies, certain services on this Website may not be available.

### **Third Party Data Processors**

In order to deliver our services, we will need to process and store your personal information and may need to transfer it to the relevant partners for processing both inside and outside the European Economic Area (EEA). These third parties simply process data on behalf of TES Global and have no right to use, disclose or transfer your personal data in any other way. By submitting your personal information, you consent to such processing and transfers in connection with your use of our services.

### **Security and possibility of international transfer**

Please note that countries outside the EEA may not have the same level of protection as countries within the EEA, but we always demand that those parties to whom we transfer data adhere to the same security procedures that we follow ourselves. By submitting your personal information, you consent to such processing and transfers in connection with such orders, offers or services and for any other purposes to which you consent at the time you provide the information.

### **Additional Terms**

In some circumstances it may be necessary for us to use, share or transfer your personal data in other ways and we will let you know about this additional use of your personal data where relevant.

### **Changes to the Privacy Statement**

From time to time we may be required or, need to, update this Privacy Statement. Where necessary and appropriate we may contact you through the email address that you have provided, to advise of a change. All changes will be accessible from all TES Global Sites through the "Privacy Policy" and notification of the last date of change will be placed at the top.

### **Legal and Contact Information**

The registered office of TES Global is: 

TES Global Limited  
26 Red Lion Square  
London WC1R 4HQ  
United Kingdom

You have a right to access the personal data held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please write to the Data Protection Officer at the above address.

We will use all reasonable efforts to answer any questions or resolve any concerns regarding your privacy promptly.

### **What are cookies?**

Cookies are harmless text files that allow a website server to recognise you when you revisit the website. There are two main types of cookies:

Transient (or session) cookies.

| 

These are set and exist for the duration of your visit to a specific website and are removed when you finish.  
They recognise you as you move, and navigate between, the different website pages so that you do not need to re-enter who you are and often can help to maintain your security.  
  
---|---  
  
Persistent (or permanent) cookies.

| 

These remain on your computer until they expire or are deleted.  
Many persistent cookies have automatic deletion dates to help ensure your computer doesn't get overloaded with cookies.  
Persistent cookies will often retain previously entered information to ease and simplify subsequent data input.  
For example: your login user ID or email address.  
  
Like most websites, this website uses both types of cookies to simplify and ease a user';s journey and experience. Cookies can also be 1st (first) or 3rd (third) party cookies:

1st Party :

| 

These are owned and created by us for the website you're viewing.  
  
---|---  
  
3rd Party :

| 

These are owned and created by an independent company. Usually this is a company partnering to provide services to us as owners of the website.  
  
We use both our own (first-party) and partner companies' (third-party) cookies to facilitate and support a simpler and more secure website experience for our users

### **What we use cookies for**

We use cookies to:

  * Gather information on a user';s journey across our sites
  * Ensure your privacy is protected in our secure sites
  * Store your login details for our secure sites
  * Temporarily store input information in any of our calculators, tools, illustrations and demonstrations
  * Store details of your marketing, product and business preferences to improve our targeting to you and enhance your journey through our sites and partner sites
  * Evaluate our sites' advertising and promotional effectiveness (we own the anonymous data collected and don't share it with anyone)  

We don't and will never:

  * use cookies to track your Internet usage after leaving one of our sites
  * store personal information in them that others could read and understand
  * sell or distribute cookie information without your prior consent.

### **Cookies we use on our sites**

The following two tables provide a list of all cookies used on our sites with a brief information of their purpose and their key attributes.

Table of 1st (first) party cookies

**Name**

| 

**Domain(s)**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Expires**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

tes.com  
community.tes.com  
account.tes.com

| 

Used to establish a unique session for the user that lasts for the duration of the visit.

| 

End of each session (visit)  
  
CSAnonymous

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Cookie written when a user is not logged on to the Community site

| 

20 minutes  
  
CommunityServer-UserCookie2101

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Cookie written when a user is not logged on to the Community site. Used to track the activity of the user 

| 

Session cookie  
  
CommunityServer-LastVisitUpdated2101

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Cookie written when a user is not logged on to the Community site. Used to track the activity of the user 

| 

1 year  
  
ui:colour

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Used to store a user';s forum colour selection on the site

| 

10 years 10 months  
  
CommunityServer-AutoLoginCookie

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Cookies used to store the user';s preference for whether or not to be logged on automatically the next time they visit the site

| 

20 minutes  
  
.CommunityServer

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Cookie written when a user is authenticated on the TES Community /Forum website

| 

Session cookie  
  
tsl-comp

| 

.tes.com

| 

Used to capture a user';s response to a competition pop up window - for example to stop the pop up re-appearing

| 

2nd January 2022  
  
TesApplication

| 

tes.com

| 

Cookie written when a user is authenticated on the tes.com website. As this cookie is defined as intrusive, the unique values in the cookie are encrypted.

| 

Session cookie  
  
TES_Compliance

| 

tes.com

| 

Used to establish an individual user's consent for the use of cookies and provide control on the messages displayed.

| 

90 days for anonymous users, 1 year for users who have ticked the cookie use box at registration.  
  
TSLCookie

| 

.tes.com

| 

SSO (Single Sign On) cookie that authenticates users on all sites within the .tes.com subdomain. As this cookie is defined as intrusive, the unique values in the cookie are encrypted.

| 

30 minutes  
  
.WVRoles

| 

.tes.com

| 

Written when a user is in the resource details page and used to check for user roles. As this cookie is defined as intrusive, the unique values in the cookie are encrypted.

| 

42 days  
  
.CSRoles

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Used to store roles a user belongs to. As this cookie is defined as intrusive, the unique values in the cookie are encrypted.

| 

42 days  
  
CommunityServer-UserCookie9999

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Tracks the page activity of a user and indirectly may be considered to be potentially intrusive.

| 

1 year  
  
CommunityServer-LastVisitUpdated-9999

| 

community.tes.com

| 

Tracks the page activity of a user and indirectly may be considered to be potentially intrusive.

| 

Session cookie  
  
**Name**

| 

**Domain(s)**  
  
---|---  
master | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
slave | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
test | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
searcht | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
tour | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
changes | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
WikispacesLogoutCookie | 

wikispaces.com  
wikispaces.net  
  
Table of 3rd (third) party cookies

**3rd Party**

| 

**Name**

| 

**Domain(s)**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Expires**  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utma

| 

tes.com

community.tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site.

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site.

The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google

| 

2 years  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utmb

| 

tes.com

community.tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site.

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site.

The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google

| 

20 minutes  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utmc

| 

tes.com

community.tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site.

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site.

The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google

| 

Session cookie  
  
Google Analytics

| 

_utmz

| 

tes.com

community.tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site.

We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site.

The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.  
Click here for an overview of privacy at Google

| 

6 months  
  
Omniture

| 

s_sq

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

undefined_s

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

20 minutes  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

s_evar33

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

s_evar32

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

s_evar31

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

s_invisit

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

20 minutes  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

s_vnum

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

30 days  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

s_cc

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

ev5

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

ev6

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Omniture/  
SiteCatalyst

| 

ev7

| 

tes.com

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.

| 

Session cookie  
  
Nielsen Netrating cookie

| 

IMRID

| 

.tes.com

| 

Used by Nielsen-Netratings to monitor website usage

| 

Session cookie  
  
### **Cookies categorised as intrusive**

Cookies can be categorised as being 'intrusive' or not in relation to storing any data items that could potentially identify some aspect of an individual user's identity; whether real or a pseudonym.

Whilst in legal interpretations there are degrees of intrusiveness, TES Global has adopted the more cautious definition where any cookie that has a single identifying data item is categorised as 'intrusive'. All intrusive cookies, whether session or persistent, are stored in encrypted form to protect against any possibility of accidental or unintended disclosure.

### **Changing your cookie settings**

To enable or disable cookies, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the 'Help', 'Tools' or 'Edit' facility). Alternatively, an external resource is available at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) providing specific information about cookies and how to manage them.

Please note that if you set your browser to disable cookies, you may not be able to access secure areas of this website, such as any online services that require registration.

### **Secure online services**

Any secure online services you subscribe to will probably use cookies to enable information about you and your preferences to be stored and to help protect your account and information. In such circumstances, cookies are essential to the service being provided securely and effectively.

If you choose to decline providing consent to use of cookies, it is unlikely that you will be able to continue to use the service.

### **Privacy and Electronic Communications Regulations**

A revision of the EU e-Privacy Directive requires that organisations must obtain prior consent from users for the use of cookies, which may be deemed to be intrusive on the user's privacy.

We are currently working towards implementing the new requirements in line with guidance from the United Kingdom Information Commissioner.
